greenpeace.org 2018-06-14

# Privacy and Cookies - Greenpeace International

Greenpeace believes you have a fundamental right to privacy on the web, and we work to protect your security online. This policy applies to [www.greenpeace.org/international](http://www.greenpeace.org/international); different specific web properties (e.g. campaign sites) may use the same or have site-specific privacy and cookies policies. We will always seek your approval for other use of your data if your consent is not covered by this policy. 

**INTRODUCTORY NOTES**

  1. This website privacy statement is designed to be published on Greenpeace International’s website.
  2. This website privacy statement is designed to give general information, seeking to meet the requirements of the GDPR, to individuals whose personal data Greenpeace International collects in their capacity as visitor to a Greenpeace International website.
  3. This document is not designed to be addressed to Greenpeace International’s employees or other staff members or other individuals who deal with Greenpeace International (i.e. other than as casual website visitors) in their personal capacity.

## **Greenpeace and data privacy**

Greenpeace International and the independent national/regional Greenpeace organisations in the Greenpeace network (together: ‘ ** _Greenpeace’_** ) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This privacy statement does not apply to the national/regional Greenpeace websites that are managed by the national/regional Greenpeace organisations (‘NROs’) themselves. You can find the privacy policy of each Greenpeace NRO website by clicking on “Privacy Statement” or “Privacy Policy” in the local language in the footer of their homepage.

This privacy statement sets out the basis on which we will process any personal information that we may collect about you as a visitor to our website. We therefore ask you to read this privacy statement carefully.

### **The information that we collect about you**

We may collect and process the following information about you:

  * **Information that you give us** : This is information about you that you give to us by: (i) making use of our website and the options on our website ( _e.g._ in the event you would sign a petition or make donation), (ii) subscribing to the receipt of updates by email, (iii) contacting us for information or help, by (iv) signing your name on a list of signatures, (v) by becoming a donor via other ways than the internet, or (vi) by participating in Greenpeace campaigns. It may include, for example, your name, address, email address and telephone number. 
  * **Information that our website and other systems collect about you** :
    * If you visit our website third parties (Analytics) will collect some information about you and your visit, such as your browser type and version and the pages on our site that you visit. Analytics will not collect the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your device to the internet. [You can ask Google](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/3024190?hl=en) to provide an extraction of your data related to Greenpeace International website. 
    * Our website may also download “cookies” to your device – this is described in our [cookie statement](https://dev.p4.greenpeace.org/international/privacy/#greenpeace-international-cookies-policy) (below)
    * If you exchange emails, telephone conversations or other electronic communications (including comments on this website) with our employees and other staff members, our information technology systems will record details of those conversations, sometimes including their content.

  * **Information that third parties collect about you on our website by performing actions** : This is information about you that you give to third parties (such as Facebook, Google and Twitter) by making use of the social network sharing buttons and widgets available on our website.

  * **Information that third parties collect about you on our website by browsing it** : This is information about you recorded / tracked by third parties just by making use of the website itself, such as navigating from one page to another (this event will be tracked) or by viewing an embedded Facebook video (if you are logged in Facebook) .

### **The use of your information we collect**

We may use your information for the following purposes:

  * to make your actions known on our website and to third parties. For example, your name may appear together with your comments on our website. To inspire others to take action, we may also show your name and a summary of what you have just done on our website, for instance, if you sign a petition or make a donation. If you petition someone using our website – for example a government official or company CEO – then we may send your name and email address with your message to them;
  * to send you updates and alerts by email, mail, instant messaging, push notifications or telephone.

We will only process your personal information as necessary for the purposes described above. In doing so, we will consider the balance between your privacy and our interest in processing and refrain from processing if your privacy interest overrides our legitimate interest.

[In exceptional circumstances we may also be required by law to disclose or otherwise process your personal information. We will tell you, when we ask you to provide information about yourself, if provision of the requested information is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation or, on the other hand, if it is purely voluntary and there will be no implications if you decline to provide the information. If you are uncertain as to Greenpeace’s need for information that we request from you, please contact the Greenpeace representative asking for the information, or Contact us (see below), with your query.]

### **Disclosure and international transfer of your information**

We may disclose personal information about you where we have obtained your consent or where it is reasonably necessary for the various purposes set out above:

  * to Greenpeace national/regional organisations (‘NROs’) which are based in the country you took action from in this International website;
  * to service providers who host our website or other information technology systems or otherwise hold or process your information on our behalf, under strict conditions of confidentiality and security;
  * to judicial authorities or other public authorities, in case our legal or moral responsibility compels us to do so (e.g. if you express intent about performing a terrorist activity); 
  * or litigation counterparties, in any country or territory, although only if we are legally required to do so and have no satisfactory basis or prospect to challenge disclosure.

These disclosures may involve transferring your personal information overseas. If you are dealing with us within the European Economic Area, you should be aware that this may include transfers to countries outside the European Economic Area, which do not have similarly strict data privacy laws. In those cases, where we transfer personal data to the independent Greenpeace NROs or our service providers, we will ensure that our arrangements with them are governed by data transfer agreements or mechanisms, designed to ensure that your personal information is protected (including, where appropriate, under an agreement on terms approved for this purpose by the European Commission).

Please Contact us (see below) if you would like to know whether any such agreements are in place or, if so, to see a copy.

### **Retention and deletion of your information**

Greenpeace International intends to keep your personal information accurate and up-to-date. We will delete the information that we hold about you when we no longer need it ** _._**

We will retain your information for no longer than _2 years_ after our most recent communication with you, after which it will be deleted or anonymised, unless we have a legal obligation to retain it for a longer period. Contact us for more information.

### **Your rights**

You may have a right of access to the personal information that we hold about you, and to some related information, under data protection law.

  * You can also require any inaccurate personal information to be corrected or deleted.
  * You can object to our use of your personal information for direct marketing purposes at any time and you may have the right to object to our processing of some or all of your personal information (and require them to be deleted) in some other circumstances.
  * In some circumstances, you may also have a “data portability” right to require us to transfer your personal data to you or to a new service provider (e.g. if you wish your data to be transferred from GPI to another Greenpeace organisation). 

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please Contact us as set out below. We are obliged to request proof of identity before access to your personal information is given.

If you would like us to remove your information from our mailing list, you can click the “ **Unsubscribe** ” link at the bottom of any email we sent to you or Contact us as set out below. 

You can also lodge a complaint about our processing of your personal information with the body regulating data protection in your country (details are available [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm)).

### **Security measures**

We have implemented appropriate technical and organisational measures to secure personal data against loss or against any form of unlawful processing. Our donation pages are secured using Secure Sockets Layer ( **SSL** ), a security protocol that provides communications privacy over the Internet in a way that is designed to prevent eavesdropping, tampering, or message forgery.

Only employees who require to access information about supporters and website visitors to perform their work are granted access to your personal data.

### **Contact us**

We welcome questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy statement and our processing of personal information.

Please email us on [**_supporter.services.int@greenpeace.org_**](mailto:supporter.services.int@greenpeace.org) ** __**

**_or contact us via:_**

_Greenpeace International_

_Ottho Heldringstraat 5_

_1066 AZ Amsterdam_

_The Netherlands_

_Tel: +31 20 7182000_

_Fax: +31 20 7182002_

### **Changes to this policy**

Any changes we make to this privacy statement in the future will be posted to our website and also available if you Contact Us as set out above.

Please check back frequently to see any changes.

**Last updated: 8 June, 2018**

* * *

## Greenpeace International cookies policy

We want to ensure that you enjoy browsing our website. In order to enhance your experience and collect information about your use of our site, we place “cookies” onto your computer.

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognises that cookie:

  * cookies allow our systems to recognise the user’s device and make any presettings immediately available
  * as soon as a user accesses the platform, a cookie is sent to the hard disk of the respective user’s computer

Cookies are useful because they:

  * allow a website to recognise a user’s device and to target the content displayed to the user’s interests
  * help us to improve our website
  * offer you a better service more tailored to your requirements
  * enable us to recognise your device when you return to our website
  * store information about your favourite activities on the website, thereby allowing us to tailor our website to your individual interests. This may, for example, include advertising according to your personal interests and accelerate the rate at which we can deal with your queries

By using our website you agree that, unless you have set your computer’s browser to reject them, we can place the types of cookies set out below on your device and use that data in accordance with this policy.

You can find more information about cookies at:[ www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/), for a video about cookies check [www.youtube.com/watch?v=TBR-xtJVq7E](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TBR-xtJVq7E) .

### **Types of cookies**

There are two broad types of cookies – ‘first party cookies’ and ‘third party cookies’:

  * **_First party cookies_** are cookies that are served directly by the website operator to your computer, and are often used to recognise your computer when it revisits that site and to remember your preferences as you browse the site. Basically, these are our cookies.
  * **_Third party cookies_** are served by a service provider on behalf of the website operator, and can be used by the service provider to recognise your computer when you visit _other_ websites. Third party cookies are most commonly used for website analytics or advertising purposes.

### **Use of cookies**

This table explains the cookies that may be placed on your machine while using this website and why.

Name | Purpose | Expiration  
---|---|---  
“greenpeace” | Used by Greenpeace International to track if you have accepted the use of cookies on our website or not | This cookie expires 1 year from set/update  
“wordpress_google_apps_login” | Used by Greenpeace International to store the logged in state of users who have an account in our website | This cookie expires when you close your browser  
“_ga”  | Used by Google Analytics to distinguish users | This cookie expires 2 years from set/update  
“_gid” | Used by Google Analytics to distinguish users | This cookie expires 24 hours from set/update  
“_dc_gtm_N7SG829” | Used by Google Analytics (via Google Tag Manager) to throttle request rate | This cookie expires 1 minute from set/update  
“AMP_TOKEN” | Used by Google Analytics to retrieve a Client ID from AMP Client ID service. 

Other possible values indicate opt-out, inflight request or an error retrieving a Client ID from AMP Client ID service.

| This cookie expires between 30 seconds and one year (depending on whether it is being used) from set/update  
“_gac_10290164” | Used by Google Analytics to link user ID to campaign related information. 

For example, if Google Analytics and AdWords accounts are linked, AdWords website conversion tags will read this cookie unless you opt-out.

| This cookie expires 90 days from set/update  
“__utma” | Used by Google Analytics to distinguish users and sessions. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and no existing __utma cookies exists. 

The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.

| This cookie expires 2 years from set/update  
“__utmt” | Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate. | This cookie expires 10 minutes from set/update  
“__utmb” | Used by Google Analytics to determine new sessions/visits. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and no existing __utmb cookies exists. 

The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.

| This cookie expires 30 minutes from set/update  
“__utmz” | Used by Google Analytics to store the traffic source or campaign that explains how the user reached your site. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics. | This cookie expires 6 months from set/update  
“__utmv” | Used by Google Analytics to store visitor-level custom variable data. This cookie is created when a developer uses the [_setCustomVar](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/methods/gaJSApiBasicConfiguration?hl=en-GB#_gat.GA_Tracker_._setCustomVar) method with a visitor level custom variable.  
This cookie was also used for the deprecated _setVar method. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics. | This cookie expires 2 years from set/update  
“usbl” | 

Used by [Usabilla](https://support.usabilla.com/hc/en-us/articles/115003780472-Usabilla-cookies-and-localStorage) for identifying new and returning visitors who are potentially presented a slide out survey. Furthermore this cookie is being used to identify visitors who already have seen the slide out survey, so it won’t be shown again. This is not cookie that tracks cross domain and is purely used for functional reasons.

| 

This cookie expires when the survey is switched off within the Usabilla software  
  
“Checkpoint” and “lp”   | Used by [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/) to authenticate your identity on Facebook or Instagram | This cookie expires when you close your browser  
  
Greenpeace International does not govern the publication of third-party cookies. Please visit the relevant third parties’ website if you want to understand more about these cookies, such as [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/), [Twitter](https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/twitter-cookies#), [Instagram](https://help.instagram.com/1896641480634370?ref=ig), [YouTube](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies) or [Soundcloud](https://soundcloud.com/pages/cookies/05-2018).

If you do not want to use cookies, you can set your browser so that the storage of cookies is not accepted.

If you only want to accept our own cookies but not the cookies of our service providers and partners, select the “block third-party cookies” (or similar setting in your browser).

### **Change your cookies preferences**

### Which cookies would you like to accept?

Please select which cookies you are willing to store.

User-experience cookies

These cookies will provide you a better experience of our website. You will be able to hide the cookies acceptance banner and use the website features better. The non-acceptance of these cookies will give you a cookie-free experience.

Performance Cookies

These cookies help improving the performance of Greenpeace.org. They are set to collect data such as how long users stay on a page or which links are clicked. This helps us make better content based on your experience navigating the website.

Most web browsers allow some control over cookies through browser settings (e.g. notifications of new cookies, disabling cookies and deleting cookies).  Click your browser type below to go directly to the browser user guide to learn how to disable or erase cookies.

Blocking all cookies will, however, have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

### **Use of Google Analytics**

Greenpeace uses Google Analytics to gather visitors’ use of our website and analyze the data to help us maintain and improve the design of our website. Google Analytics generates statistical and other information about website use by means of cookies, which are stored on users’ computers.

**Should you not be willing to get the analytics cookies, please change you cookies settings above (‘change your cookies preferences’).**  

As mentioned before, Google Analytics cookies used in this website are **_utma, _utmb, _utmc, _utmz, _ga and _gid** – and they **all collect information in an anonymous form** , including the number of visitors to the site, browser ClientID (to identify returning users, for example), where visitors come to the site from and the pages they visited. Here’s the[ privacy overview of Google Analytics](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245), the [Google Analytics Cookie Usage on Websites](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage?hl=en-GB) and here [how to easily opt-out of Google Analytics cookies](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

As of May 2018, Google Analytics introduced the [Data Retention controls](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/7667196), giving organizations the ability to set the amount of time before user-level and event-level data stored by Google Analytics is automatically deleted from Analytics’ servers.

Such retention period applies to user-level and event-level data associated with cookies, user-identifiers (e.g., User-ID) and advertising identifiers (not applicable in Greenpeace websites anyway). **For Greenpeace International, the Data Retention control for Google Analytics is set to 26 months**. Once again, Analytics will not collect the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your device to the internet.

Besides, it is important to mention that Google stores websites traffic information which have Google Analytics tracking code.[ Check Google’s privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and how to [opt-out of Google Analytics cookies](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

You can install the “[Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)” to prevent information about your visits to our website being sent to Google Analytics.

### **Use of social networks sharing buttons and widgets**

Beside the [customized HTML buttons](https://schier.co/blog/2014/10/22/pure-html-share-buttons.html) we installed to allow you to share Greenpeace content on Facebook and Twitter, we may embed widgets from [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/), [Twitter](https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/twitter-cookies#), [Instagram](https://help.instagram.com/1896641480634370?ref=ig), [YouTube](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies), [Soundcloud](https://soundcloud.com/pages/cookies/05-2018) and other social media on our website to provide an enhanced experience.

These social networking  widgets come from web servers which may track your behaviour on our website and may combine this with other information about you originating from other websites. You can install a browser add-ons like “[Privacy Badger](https://www.eff.org/privacybadger)” for Chrome or “Disconnect” for[ Chrome](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/jeoacafpbcihiomhlakheieifhpjdfeo?hc=search&hcp=main) and[ Firefox](https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/user/6016894/) to control some (the first) or disable them (the second).

### **Contact us**

This website is owned and operated by Greenpeace International. If you have any questions about our cookies or this cookies policy, please [contact the webmaster](mailto:webmaster.int@greenpeace.org).
